Moving onto the Hollywood Freeway,
we have a multiple vehicle...
multiple injury accident.
An absolute mess
from VineStreet to the valley.
If you're in it,
expect a long commute.
If you're not,
seek alternate routes.
If Dan doesn 't want to do a daily rate,
we can talk about a weekly rate.
But I'm tellin' you right now,
I'm not goin' below a million.
I mean, think about it.
I'm risking my reputation...
as the host
of this country's number-one...
nationally syndicated talk show to do
a cameo in some cheap slasher flick.
I mean, why can't these guys write me
a fuckin' decent part?
You know?
I lived through the fuckin' thing.
By the way, did you talk to Cathy
about that Navy SEAL script?
Hang on a sec.
- Hello?
- Who's this?
- Who are you calling?
- Oh. You know what?
- I'm sorry. I have the wrong number.
- That's okay.
Wait a minute. I know your voice.
You sound a lot like that guy on TV.
Um, Cotton Weary.
- I do, huh?
- Yeah.
I think he's got
a really sexy voice.
- Well, thank you.
- Wait a minute.
You are Cotton, aren't you?
Oh, my God.
I am talking to Cotton Weary.
I can't believe this.
You got me. Look, I've--
I've got someone on the other line.
Can you hold on one second?
I'll be right back, I promise.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Andrea, uh, I gotta call you back.
Someone's on the other line.
So, uh, you a big 100% Cotton fan?
- Yeah! One hundred and ten percent.
- That's very good.
So, um, why don't you tell me
who you are?
Ooh! You're a naughty boy, Cotton.
Now, what would your girlfriend say?
What makes you think
I have a girlfriend?
I know you do.
- I'm right outside her bathroom door.
- Who is this?
She's in the shower.
She's got a nice little voice.
Let's come in for a closer look.
She's very pretty, Cotton.
A step up from
Maureen Prescott.
Speaking of which,
let's play a little game.
Answer right,
your girlfriend lives.
Answer wrong, she dies.
- Where's Maureen's daughter, Sidney?
- Who the fuck is this?
Somebody who'd kill to know
where Sidney Prescott is!
One chance, Cotton!
You've got connections. Where is she?
You listen to me, you fuckin' psycho.
You lay a finger on Christine...
- and I swear to God I'll kill you.
- Wrong answer!
No! Wait!
Hello? Shit!
- Hey!
- Get outta the way!
- You just hit me!
- Move!
Christine, if you're there,
pick up the phone!
Christine, pick up the phone!
Oh, shit!
You have reached 911.
Due to the volume of calls--
Someone pick up the goddam phone!
Move outta the way!
Shit! Shit!
Cotton, is that you?
Cotton?
Honey?
Okay, Cotton.
You know I don't like
your Stab games.
- Who is it? Who's there?
- Christine?
Hon, you all right?
- I'm home.
-Jesus! You scared the shit outta me.
- You're not gonna believe
what just happened to me.
- What are you talking about?
- Get the hell out of here!
- Okay. Okay, I'm sorry, babe.
I didn't mean to scare you that bad.
It's me. Come on, open the door.
- What are you doing?
- What?
- What the fuck are you doing?
I was-- I was just, you know, trying
to take the game to the next level.
- I'm sorry. Come on,
open the door, Chris.
- The game?
- Yeah, the game!
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about how much fun it's
gonna be to rip your insides out!
Now, open the fuckin' door, Christine!
- Oh, my God!
- Now you're fuckin' history, baby!
Christine?
Hon?
The recent epidemic of roadrage
in Los Angeles.
- Innocent commuters mercilessly
terrorized, even killed...
- Chris?
- by these madmen of the freeway.
- Don't mess around, okay?
We're gonna make them confront their
victims face-to-face, mano a mano...
right here on 100% Cotton.
There is carnage on our streets.
And remember, it could happen to you.
Tomorrow on 100% Cotton!
Roadrage.
L.A. drivers fight back.
The news is next on channel six with our
exclusive entertainment report live...
from tonight's celebrity
premiere in Hollywood...
followed by--
Oh, shit.
Chris?
Is that you, babe?
Chris, if you're in there,
open the door. Okay, honey?
Chris? Come on, baby.
Open the door.
Chris! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Jesus!
- It's me, Chris. What are you doin'?
- Stay back.
Stay back.
- Chris, what's goin' on, babe?
- You've gone crazy. That's what!
- Chris, was somebody in the house?
- No! Get back!
Okay, okay, okay.
Just calm down, okay?
- Why do you want to kill me?
- What are you talking about?
- Why do you wanna kill me?
- Gimme the club. All right, honey?
Gimme the club.
Gimme the club, please.
Christine, get outta the way!
Behind you!
Shit!
It was a simple game, Cotton.
You should've told me where Sidney was.
Now, you lose.
Come on.
Come on, Cherokee.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
Hey, it's Laura from Monterrey reporting
to work. Can you patch me in?
- Sure. Thanks, Laura.
- Thank you.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
How can I help you?
Hi. Um, do I have to say my name?
No, you don't have to say anything
you don't want to say.
- How can I help?
- Um--
I'm 18 years old,
and I have a boyfriend.
- Sometimes he hits me.
- It's okay.
- You can talk to me, all right?
- Thanks.
So, in closing, as
the future journalists of America...
there is one thing
that you need to remember.
Being the best means being willing
to do what the others would not.
Break the rules.
Stop at nothing.
Be willing to have the world hate you,
because that is the only way...
that you'll get the story,
the facts and the fame.
Thank you.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Yes?
So you're saying that we should
be ready to go out...
and cut each other's throats
because that's what you did.
- Metaphorically, yes.
- Well, tell me, Miss Weathers.
- Was it worth it?
- I'm so sorry. We're out of time.
Gale Weathers, anchor woman for
Total Entertainment.
Thank you very much!
There is a young man outside
who wants to see you.
- He says he's with the police.
- The police?
- Detective Mark Kincaid, L.A.P.D.
- Hello.
- That's quite an impressive resume.
- Thank you.
I assume you're not here
for an autograph.
I'm here because
Cotton Weary's been murdered.
- Someone killed Cotton?
- And his girlfriend.
Someone who left something
he wanted us to see.
I'll show you this because
you're the Woodsboro authority
and because you knew him.
But I promise you,
if you share this with the world,
it's you I'll be arresting.
I swear on my Pulitzer Prize, which
I plan to win one day, Detective.
This was left on Cotton Weary's body.
You have any idea who the girl might be?
Oh, my God.
This is Maureen Prescott.
This is Sidney Prescott's mother.
Hollywood is reeling today
from news...
of the murder of controversial
talkshow host Cotton Weary.
Weary had only recently finished
shooting a cameo as himself...
in the film
Stab 3, Return to Woodsboro...
the third and final part
of the famous horror series...
based on the Woodsboro
and Windsor College murders.
Before his rise to television fame,
Cotton had been imprisoned...
and was later exonerated for the murder
of Maureen Prescott, his former lover--
Just yesterday, Cotton Weary was
shooting here at Sunrise Studios...
his first cameo
in a feature film, Stab 3.
Security here is tight, but we'll see
if we can get a statement. Excuse me.
Always a controversial man--
Channel Eight news.
We gotta get in. We gotta get in.
No press beyond this point.
Alone at night
he crosses flames
Ashe makes a fist
with his red right hand
Look, you're worried about the movie,
then protect the movie, okay?
Hire more security. Hire the National
Guard.Just don't kill the movie.
Violence in cinema
is a big deal right now, Roman.
This is not the kind of news
this studio is after.
So if we stop making
scary movies, what?
All the psychos in the world
will retire? Come on.
I've been makin' horror movies for
30 years, never had a psycho problem.
He was your goddamn idea, guys.
All right?
An ex-con with a trashy talk show?
He must've pissed people off every day.
Detectives, there's no reason
to presume that Cotton's death...
had anything to do
with this movie, is there?
He was making a movie called Stab.
He was stabbed.
Probably some psycho fan pissed off
they killed Randy in Stab 2.
Well, Tyson, that'd make you next,
wouldn't it?
I am not a Randy substitute.
I'm my own character.
Named Ricky,
who works at the video store.
It's an homage.
Hey! What if the killer's
Sidney Prescott?
I mean, what the hell ever happened to
her? She's probably off in the woods...
livin' like
the fuckin' Unabomber, man.
I'm starting to see why
Tori Spelling and David Schwimmer
didn't want to come back.
Guys, this was about Cotton.
We are not in any danger.
"We are not in any danger,"
says Candy, page 15.
I don't see you leavin'.
You think serious black actors
my age can just throw away jobs?
It's all a business now. They got
Usher doing Pinter off-Broadway.
L.L. Cool J's
Shakespearin' in the park.
- Yeah!
- Maybe it's not meant to be.
Not meant to be? You win that
talent search for the new Sidney.
50,000 girls and they pick you. You
gotta be praying this movie keeps going.
Of course I am, but not
at the expense of people's lives.
Oh. Cue the violins, right?
Jesus.
Deja voodoo.
We need this area cleared, please.
Clear it.
- Gale Weathers! Oh, my God!
- Shit.
I-- Listen,
I-I-- I know we've never met...
and I don't mind you never returning
my calls, but I have to tell you...
after two films,
I feel like I am in your mind.
Well, that would explain
my constant headaches.
You know, I'm sorry things didn't
work out on 60 Minutes II.
- But Total Entertainment,
that's a pretty good fallback.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry that things didn't
work out with Brad Pitt...
but being single,
that's a pretty good fallback.
Gives me more time
for my work.
After all, Gale Weathers,
you're such a complex character.
Oh, and to be played by an actress
with such depth and range.
Uh,Jennifer,
Nick said you wanted to--
Gale.
Dewey.
Well, surprise, surprise.
Someone dies and Gale comes running.
Gale, I think you'll really appreciate
my character work in this one.
- Someone's helped me
understand the real you.
- Someone?
Your ruthless ambition,
your private self-loathing...
and that lost and lonely
little girl inside.
Lost and lonely what?
You heard me.
Thanks, Dewey, I'll return it.
Lost and lonely what?
- Little girl inside.
- I thought you were
supposed to be in Woodsboro.
Well, I'm surprised
you thought about me at all.
Listen, I gotta get back to work.
I really don't have time for this.
- Wait a minute. You work here?
- Yeah.
The movie needed
a technical advisor.
Someone who went through the real
experience, knew the real people.
- Hey, Dewey.
- Hey, Tom.
Hey! It's the real Gale Weathers.
Real from top to bottom.
Tom Prinze.
Watch your show all the time.
You're so right. Pop culture
is the politics ofthe 21 st century.
- Thank you.
- And that story that you did...
last month on me crashing my car?
-Wow, was that ever powerful journalism.
-Right, uh--
I especially liked the way
you implied that it was caused
by drinking and drugs.
And that the tyre blowout was faked.
That was great.
Tom, sometimes in journalism
you have to--
Are you parked in the lot?
'Cause I should check to make sure...
that nobody's messed
with your brake line.
Who's he supposed to be?
He's playing you? Him?
What?
I did not come here
to fight with you, Dewey.
- Cotton's killer left a picture.
- Of Sid's mom.
- The detectives told me.
- Well, does Sidney know about it?
Listen, Sidney doesn't need
you and your camera in her life.
Do you see a camera?
Right. You bought me
this purse, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- Look, it's-it's a habit.
-I-I walk outta the house, I turn it on.
-What the hell is this?
- It's like perfume.
- Gale Weathers?
- Could I be more popular?
- No press.
Mo press on set.
Get that woman outta here.
- Yes, Mr Milton. Let's go.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Where is Detective Kincaid?
- I am working with Kincaid, Dewey.
- Come on. Move along, miss. Let's go.
Rules are rules, Gale.
But, really, it was great seeing you.
Stab 3 is a closed set. But just up
ahead is the old Seinfeld stage.
Now, does anybody
need a potty break?
- Oh, I do.
- Yeah, me too.
Okay, let go!
Thanks for your help, boys.
Holy shit, Silent Bob. It's that
TV news chick, Connie-fuckin'-Chung!
Hey, Connie, how's Maury?
Dude, I think she likes me.
See how she's lookin' at me?
It's happening again.
Cotton had a lot
of enemies, Sid.
The police aren't saying
it's related to us.
Do you ever think about her?
Your mom?
None of this would've
ever happened if she hadn't--
if she hadn't--
Why'd she have
so many secrets, Dad?
Listen, maybe it's time
you came home.
I'm worried about you, kid. Out here
by yourself. You never see anyone.
The only people you talk to
don't even know your real name.
It's as if you don't exist.
That's the idea. Psychos
can't kill what they can't find.
Sid, come here.
Mother needs to talk to you.
Everything you touch, Sid, dies!
You're poison.
You're just like me.
Oh, my God!
What have they done to me?
They'll do it to you.
- They'll do it to you, baby.
- Mom?
Roman?
Stab 3.
Jesus, I gotta get a new agent.
Roman?
Someone here?
Stan, my man.
He does good work, huh?
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Fuck you very much.
- Tyson, go to hell.
- Well, excuse us, Sarah. Makeup tests.
Yeah, makeup. You can use it.
Damn it, have you seen Roman?
Look, everyone in the office
has gone home already.
- He said it was important.
- Everything's important to Roman.
Oh, shit!
- Director's office.
- Sarah, it's Roman.
I'm sorry I'm running late. I'm still
on the 405. I'm about ten minutes away.
Oh, it's no problem. I'm just
lookin' at your music video awards.
Since I got you on thephone, let's--
let's talk about your character, okay?
What character? I'm Candy,
the chick who gets killed second.
- I'm only in two scenes.
- You're not happy with your part.
I'm not happy that I am
35 playing a 21-year-old.
I'm not happy
that I have to die naked.
And I'm not happy that my character is
too stupid to have a gun in the house...
after her boyfriend's
been cut into fish sticks.
Great, okay.
So let's--let's run the lines.
Fine.
Page28.
Candy's big moment.
Page 28.
Ring-ring.
Hello?
- Hello?
- Who's this?
- This is Candy.
Hang on.
Let me get some clothes.
See? I don't understand why I have
to start the scene in the shower.
The whole shower thing's been done.
Vertigo. Hello?
And I mean, my boyfriend just died.
Why am I showering?
Why don't we just read the scene?
Candy. Nice name. Is that like
Candy Cane or Candy Apple?
Whatever.
Come on.
Who is this?
I think you have
the wrong number.
- But you know my favourite name?
- I'm hanging up right now.
It's Sarah.
Roman, that's not the line.
It is in my script.
Has there been another goddam rewrite?
How the fuck...
are we supposed to learn our lines when
there's a new script every 15 minutes?
It's not just a new script.
It's a new movie.
- What? What movie?
- My movie.
And it's called Sarah Gets
Skewered Like a Fuckin' Pig!
Still in character, Sarah?
Shit.
Thank you for calling
Sunrise Picture Studios.
If you'd like today's
commissary menu, press one.
Mr Bridger?
If you'd like to hear previews of
upcoming Sunrise Pictures'releases...
press four.
If you'd like information about
Sunrise Pictures' merchandise...
- Come on. Come on.
- press five.
If you're trying to reach Lot Security
or you have an emergency, press six.
Shit!
Oh! Fuck!
Look, I wanna get something straight.
I only got into this because
the police asked for my help.
- Why would the police come to you?
- Well, I did write..
the definitive book
on the Woodsboro murders.
I'm sure you just can't wait
to write another one.
- What about you?
- What about me?
You said you'd never leave Woodsboro.
"It's the only place that's real."
But now you're here.
Not with me.
Dewey, I took care ofyou.
I waited until you were well,
but I couldn't stay there.
It was like dog years. One year in
Woodsboro is like seven anywhere else.
So it's off to Paris for a week?
New York for a month? L.A. forever?
It was fucking 60 Minutes II.
- I couldn't say no. I could've
been the next Diane Sawyer.
- Wait a minute.
What's wrong with just being
Gale Weathers? I liked her.
It didn't work, Dewey.
We tried. We're different.
You used to say
that was our strength.
- Well--
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Dewey, you're not just here because
of that second-rate K-Mart...
straight-to-video
version of me, are you?
Brace yourself, Gale.
All of this is actually not about you.
All of what, Dewey?
You do know something, don't you?
- Off the record?
- Always.
Two months ago, the Woodsboro police
got a call from a woman...
who said she was with Stab 3.
She wanted to see the file
on Sid, "for research."
- And?
- The boys said no.
And she wouldn't give her name.
A month later,
the station gets broken into.
- The file room gets ransacked.
- And someone stole Sid's file?
I already removed it.
I think someone on the film
is tryin' to find Sid.
- I'm sorry, this is incredible.
- I said, "off the record."
Right.
It's Jennifer.
She needs me.
-Jennifer?
- Gotta run.
- Wait! Dewey, where are you going?
- I'm on duty.
Stop following me.
I happen to be working
for the police, damn it!
- You're not a detective, Gale.
- Neither are you, Mr Incognito.
- Uh, you left your motor running.
- Damn it.
Fans, I can handle. Fans, they want
a picture, they want a conversation.
I can handle fans!
You see this, Dewey?
I haven't had one ofthese in a year and
a half. Someone's gonna pay for this.
-Jennifer, settle down. What happened?
- I'm with him.
- You.
Like I'm ever going
to win an award playing you.
- There's been a second murder.
- Who?
- Sarah Darling.
- Where?
-At the studio.
-Where? Nancy Drew
wants to know where.
Cotton Weary. Sarah Darling.
Don't you get it?
Someone's killing them in the order
they die in the movie.
- Dewey, who gets killed third?
- Who gets killed third?
You do.
I get killed in Stab 3?
I get killed?
- Yeah.
- Dewey, where are you going?
I have to get something
from my trailer.
Your--
You live here with her?
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God!
I needed a place to stay,
and she said she liked having me around.
- Why?
- She says I make her feel safe.
- She says I'm her rock.
- Her rock?
Yeah. If you weren't so concerned
with pretensions and appearances...
you'd be able to appreciate the
positivity and emotional centeredness...
I provide a woman.
Stone, I'm headed
to the crime scene.
You stay by Jennifer's side.
I suggest a search of the grounds.
Hey, Dewdrop.
Can I have a word?
Just so it can be straight. I'm
the professional celebrity guard here.
My resume lists Julia Roberts,
Salmon Rushdie, Posh Spice.
You are the Hollywood hanger-oner.
'Cause you're just no good
as a cop any more.
Your resume reads
like the obituaries.
So how about you take suggestions
from me? All right?
Whatever you say.
Hmm. Same deal?
Found with the body?
- Yeah, Maureen Prescott again.
- This is great.
Ten more murders
and we can publish a calendar.
The old "killer playing
with the cops" routine.
Very Hannibal Lecter.
Very Seven.
Doesn't the killer come after
the cops in those movies?
Usually one cop makes it.
- And?
- One cop doesn't.
- Usually.
- Detective Kincaid.
- What do we know? Same killer?
- Hey, hey.
Terminal Entertainment,
this is a crime scene, okay?
Wallace, Miss Weathers
is working with me now.
- Thank you, Detective.
- You're welcome.
Well, in that case, I'm gonna go dust
for fingerprints with Jane Pauley.
Uh, photos, Wallace, please?
Thank you.
New pictures, same person.
Anything turn up on your research yet?
- Nothing that will help with these.
- What about an increased
police presence around Jennifer?
- She's the next one
to get killed in the script.
- She has a bodyguard.
And besides, the producers told us
that there were three different
versions of the script.
Something about trying to keep
the ending off the Internet.
You should know that.
You're the technical advisor, right?
Three versions.
Three different characters die next.
And we don't know which one
the killer read.
Hey, hold up.
All I ever wanted to do
was make a real classic lovestory.
And the studio said they'd let me.
I just had to do
a scary movie for them first.
And now we're shut down,
and I am fucked!
God, it's not the end
of the world, Roman.
That is so easy foryou to say. You can
always go back to, to MustSee TV.
You know, I have no movie,
I'm about to turn 30, and it
looks like I'm now the next target.
- What?
- You? Why you?
Do you think this wasn't a message?
- Roman Bridger?
- What?
Mr Bridger,
you didn't tell us...
you spoke with Sarah Darling
before she was murdered.
Uh, spoke with her, uh, when?
The guard said she was here
for a meeting with you.
- What meeting? I don't--
- We talked with her roommate too.
Says you called Sarah,
told her to come down to the studio.
- Roommate answered the phone.
Says it was you.
- Wait a minute. No, no.
I-I never called her.
I never told her to go anywhere.
Roommate says she knows
your voice, Mr Bridger.
Well, she wasn't speaking with me! God!
Look, I did not call Sarah Darling.
- Sarah Darling said you did.
- Someone's trying to ruin my movie.
Someone wants to kill
my movie!
All right, we'll talk about
your movie down at the station.
- All right.
- This is the scene
where you come with us.
Dewey,Jennifer--
Wait a minute.
She wasn't talking with me
on the phone. I'm coming!
I'll call him in. Battery. Mr Riley,
do you have a cell phone I can borrow?
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- God. Roman.
Remind me not
to sleep with him again.
Come here, Cherokee.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
My name is Laura. How can I help you?
Oh, Laura.
I do have a crisis.
Okay, well, whatever it is,
you can tell me.
Oh, my God.
I've killed someone, Laura.
- Are you sure ?
- Uh-huh, I'm sure.
I killed someone, I know it!
Oh, my God.
- Well, then, um--
- I did.
Then the people you need to call
are the police.
No, I need to call you!
Just you.
I'm sorry, your-your voice--
Don't you wanna know
how you can help, Laura?
Are you listening to me?
Huh?
- Who is this?
- It's Mother, Laura.
Now, be a good girl
and turn on the news.
Do as Mother tells you!
You're not my mother. How did you
get this number? Who is this?
You know your mother's voice
when you hear it!
Now, turn on the news!
And with a second cast member
murdered, Stab 3...
has been officially shut down,
prompting those involved...
to hope and pray that
these killings maybe over.
Just one question.
Do you think it's over, Sidney?
Do you?
The sky was dark this morning
Not a bird in a tree
Is this a wrap party
or is this a wrap party?
Scene 34.
"Maureen's Murder Flashback."
- I never liked that scene.
- That's 'cause you weren't in it.
Scenes 40 through 47.
- "The Prescott House Flashbacks."
- Tom, stop it.
You're scaring me.
Two people are dead.
Scaring you?
Give the sweet,
young ingenue act a rest.
- You're drunk.
- I'm coping.
I bet she fought and clawed
for that Sidney part.
I bet she stepped on any poor girl
that got in her way.
- So you asked her out and she said no?
- That has nothing to do with it.
Right.
Come on, Dewey.
Scene 50.
"Dewey Saves the Day."
She's so focused on success
that she never thinks...
about who she's hurting
to get it.
And you saved her life, like,
how many times?
Gale wants the whole world
to love her.
One person's never enough.
She's a dreamer.
-No, she's a narcissistic, psycho bitch.
-No, she's not.
She's got a good heart.
She does.
She just hides it away because
she thinks people see that as weak.
This is a good picture of you.
You look just like her.
God, Dewey.
You make it sound like
you're still in love with her.
And I left out the part
that she's cruel...
and selfish,
obsessive and annoying.
We have one Gale Weathers here.
We don't need two.
Hey, Dewdrop,
got your girlfriend out here.
Look who I found slinkin'
around the yard. The nightly news.
I wasn't slinking.
I was walking.
You were eaves dropping
at the bedroom window.
Yeah, a bedroom that
you seemed awfully at home in.
All right, let's talk.
Come on.
- What's this about, Gale?
- Did you know they released Roman?
Sarah's call didn't come
from his cell phone.
- Where did it come from then?
- A cloned cell phone. It's untraceable.
Well, thanks for the update, Gale.
Why don't you just go back home?
Dewey, wait a minute.
Just wait one second.
How old do you think
Maureen Prescott is in this picture?
- Nineteen, twenty.
- That's what I thought,
so I checked it out.
I cannot find any information about
her at this age. I mean, nothing.
She lived in Woodsboro her whole life.
Someone there must know something.
Almost her whole life.
Two years before...
she met Sidney's father,
she left Woodsboro.
No one has any idea
where she went or what she did.
I mean, it's-it's like she fell into
a black hole, Dewey! She vanished!
- So?
Why is the killer
leaving pictures of-of Maureen?
And why these pictures at-at--
at that point in her life?
I don't know! If I thought
like a homicidal maniac...
then I'd know how
a homicidal maniac thinks.
What?
-Jennifer.
-Jennifer?
Look at the buildings.
The second story. There and there.
It's the same!
It's the same street 28 years ago.
Oh, my God. Maureen Prescott was
at the back lot at Sunrise Studios!
- Oh, my God.
- I gotta make some calls.
Steven Stone
Protection Services.
Stone, where are you?
I'm just checking
your tin can, Dewdrop.
Well, come back inside
and stay with Jennifer.
Something's happened.
I have to go to the police.
Is that an order, Dewdrop? 'Cause
Steven Stone doesn't work for you.
Get back in the house, Stone.
Would I call you if it wasn 't important?
- What are you doing in there anyway?
- Me?
I'm just checking to make sure
there's no killer in here...
waitin' to off you
like he did your little sister.
What did you say?
I can't believe you said that.
That makes me...
angry!
Fucker!
Gotta call Kincaid.
Dewey, where is everybody?
- Oh, God.
-Jennifer?
Angelina?
Tom?
Oh, my God!
What happened?
Don't do that.
I'm overreacting.
Dewdrop?
- Stone?
- Oh, my God!
Oh, God, Stone!
Oh, God!
- Dewey, is he dead?
- Yeah.
Everyone back inside!
It's all right.
Don't panic.
Okay, outside. Everyone,
stay together and try to remain calm.
A phone!
- It's not mine.
Shit!
It's the fax.
"Interior, Jennifer's house. Living
room, night." It's a script page.
- W-W-What's it say?
- "With the bodyguard stabbed to death,
the five stand trapped.
- He's rewriting the movie.
- As the killer waits outside...
suddenly the fax machine
sends news of their fates."
It's a trick!
Everybody, outside!
- Outside where he can
pick us off one by one?
- Shut up!
"The killer prepares to grant
mercy to only one of them."
Don't you get it? The killer says he's
outside because he wants us here inside.
- Which one is it?
- Come on!
"Who will survive? Is it Jennifer?
Tom? Angelina? Dewey? Gale?
- The killer will give mercy to--"
- Everyone outside!
He grants mercy to who?
I wanna know what happens!
- I wanna know what happens!
- Wait for the fucking movie!
- I've gotta know! I'm goin' back in!
- No.
All right, everyone, back.
Stay together.
- What's it say?
- "And the...
killer will give mercy to...
- whoever--"
- Whoever?
Whoever?
Piece of shit.
"Whoever--
Whoever smells the--"
I can't stop
rolling down the hill!
Gale!Jennifer!
- Dewey!
Dewey, where are you?
Over here, Dewey!
- Dewey!
- Gale!
Gale, behind you!
Dewey!
Are you all right?
Yeah, never been better.
Yeah, I'm all right.
Where'd he go?
- He must've rolled under the car.
- All right, stay close.
Is he back there?
- No.
- No?
He's fast.
Could've sworn I hit him.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Thanks for saving me.
Ah, it's habit.
Oh, God.
What the fuck happened to you?
-Jennifer, wait a minute.
- Who gave you a place to stay?
-Who are you supposed to be protecting?
-Jennifer!
Hey!
My lawyer liked that.
Not as much as I did.
- Angelina?
- Tom was in the house.
- How'd you end up way over there?
- Oh, my God! Tom was in the house!
- Are we safe?
- Safe from who?
Wait a second!
Another picture.
Whoever it is is now taking credit
for Maureen Prescott's murder.
But we know who killed Maureen
Prescott. Billy Loomis and Stu Macher.
-I mean, they even told Sidney
how they did it.
- Yeah, but if I'm not mistaken...
you said in your book that
Sidney got it wrong once before.
She accused Cotton Weary
of murdering her mother.
And he was sent away for it.
Maybe there is a third killer.
Sidney might know something.
I told you.
I don't know where Sidney is.
And even if there was a third killer,
Sidney doesn't know about it.
That is for me to decide.
I need to talk to her, Mr. Riley.
She is a key element in this case.
I have a press conference in an hour.
I need to explain...
why there are three dead celebrities
and a bodyguard.
And a very angry mayor.
Okay, look, we all know this has
something to do with Stab 3.
But what we do not know is why
the killer keeps leaving pictures...
of Maureen Prescott
taken over 25 years ago.
And the photographs taken at the same
studio Stab 3 is shooting out of.
What does this
have to do with Sid?
Who knows more about Maureen
Prescott than her own daughter?
Well, Sid's dad couldn't help you,
and he was married to Maureen.
What's your problem?
Last night you were almost charcoal.
You gonna help us or what?
Do you wanna have this
conversation with a polygraph?
- Is that a threat, Detective?
- When it's a threat, you'll know it.
- Was that a threat?
- Boys, boys.
Why don't we compare
our gun calibres later?
- The issue is Maureen Prescott.
- Wrong. The issue is Sidney Prescott.
And either Mr Riley is going
to obstructjustice or he's going
to put me in touch with her.
So, where is she?
Hi, you've reached the machine.
You can leave a message.
Talk as long as you want.
Sid, it's me.
This is the fifth time I've called.
Please pick up.
I wanna make sure you're...
okay.
- Sid!
- Dewey!
What are you doing down here?
Actually, what was I doing up there?
-Jesus, Dewey. Are you okay?
- Oh, yeah, I'm all right.
- Is she all right?
- Hey, you know Gale.
It'd take a direct hit.
So the news said this was the precinct.
Who's this guy Kincaid?
Come here.
I told you to stay hidden.
- It's not safe for you to be here.
- The killer called me.
- What?
- Yeah, he found me.
I'm no more safe there than I am here,
and at least here I'm not alone.
Okay, come on.
- Detective Kincaid?
- Yeah.
There's someone here
who wants to help.
Oh, my God.
Sidney.
Is the man fast or what?
- Hi.
- Hi, Gale.
- I'm glad you're all right.
- Thank you.
- Sid, this is Detective Kincaid.
- Nice to finally meet you, Sidney.
- The killer called her.
- What? When?
- What did he say?
- Oh, you know, the usual small talk.
What's new? How you been?
How do you wanna die?
Sidney, do you have any idea
how he could've gotten your number?
He could have monitored her calls on a
scanner. Did you call her from the set?
- No.
- Do you have her number
stored in your memory?
- Phone memory!
- Oh. Yeah, guess I do.
- Has anyone else ever used your phone?
-Just Jennifer.
And you.
Hey, I'm the cop here.
You're in my office, Riley.
The killer leaves a photograph
after each murder, Sidney.
They were taken in Hollywood at the same
studio that they're shooting Stab 3.
Why didn't you tell me?
This is my mother, Dewey.
- Why didn't you say something?
- I was afraid they were bait.
Something to, you know,
trick you out of hiding.
Sidney, was she an actress or a model?
Because they look a lot
like publicity stills.
I, uh, don't know.
Detective, I wanna see
this place in the pictures.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
- Slow it down.
- Sorry.
Watch the fuckin' aliens.
I'm gonna go talk to
the studio brass about those photos.
Yeah, right.
I know where you're goin'.
- Yeah, keep an eye on Sidney.
- I know where you're goin'.
You're gonna get her some flowers
and candy, huh? Huh?
- Gimme a break.
- Yeah, gimme a call.
Just keep your eye on her.
That stairwell over there, that's
where one of the pictures was taken.
God. I can't believe
she never mentioned any of this.
- She probably just--
- Dewey!
- Sorry.
- Martha!
- Oh, my God, Sid.
- Hey, hold it right there! Hey!
- Don't shoot!
- I'm only 17.
- It's okay. We know her.
We do?
Tell me that's his ex-girlfriend,
I'll shoot myself.
- It's Martha Meeks, Randy's sister.
- Randy's sister?
- Yeah, can't you tell?
- We miss you in Woodsboro, guys.
- Martha, what are you doing here?
- There's something you guys should see.
Told ya I'd make
a movie someday. Huh?
- Oh, my God.
- Well, if you're watching this tape...
it means, as I feared, I did not
survive these killings...
here at Windsor College,
and that giving up my virginity...
to Karen Kolchakat the video store
was probably not a good idea.
- Karen Kolchak?
- Yes, Karen Kolchak.
- "Creepy Karen"?
- Shut up! She's a sweet person, okay?
We were workin'late. We were puttin'
away some videos in the porno section...
and, you know, shit happens.
- Open the door, Randy!
- Fifteen minutes.
- It's my room too!
- Paul,15 minutes.
I'm leaving my legacy.
Fifteen minutes, Paul!
Damn! Anyway...
the reason I'm here is to help you so
that my death will not be in vain.
That my life's work will help save some
other poor soul from getting mutilated.
If this killer does come back
and he's for real...
there are a few things
that you gotta remember.
Is this simply another sequel?
Well, if it is, same rules apply.
But here's the critical thing.
If you find yourself dealing...
with an unexpected back-story
and ap reponderance...
of exposition,
then the sequel rules do not apply.
Because you're not dealing with
the sequel. You are dealing with...
the concluding chapter
of a trilogy.
- Trilogy.
- That's right. It's
a rarity in the horror field...
but it does exist, and it is
a force to be reckoned with.
Because true trilogies are all about
going back to the beginning...
and discovering something
that wasn 't true from the get-go.
Godfather, Jedi,
all revealed something...
that we thought was true
that wasn 't true.
So if it is a trilogy
you are dealing with...
here are some super
trilogy rules.
One: You've got a killer
who's gonna be superhuman.
Stabbing him won't work.
Shooting him won't work.
Basically, in the third one, you've
gotta cryogenically freeze his head...
decapitate him or blowhim up.
Number two: Anyone, including
the main character, can die.
This means you, Sid.
I'm sorry. It's the final chapter.
It could be fuckin' Reservoir Dogs
by the time this thing is through.
Number three: The past will
come back to bite you in the ass.
Whatever you think you know
about the past, forget it.
The past is not at rest!
Any sins you think...
were committed in the past are about
to break out and destroy you.
So in closing,
let me say...
goodluck, Godspeed...
and for some of you,
I'll see you soon.
'Cause the rules say some of you
ain't gonna make it. I didn't.
Not if you're watching this tape.
Thank you. And you be careful.
Say hi to your folks for me.
You be careful too, Sid.
- Bye, Dewey. Come visit us soon.
- I will, Martha.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
I've got an idea.
I'll hook up with you guys later.
- Do you want us to come with you?
- I work better alone.
Why don't you try to figure out where
those other pictures were taken.
- I can see nothing's changed.
- No.
Oh, shit.
Hello!
-Jeez.
- What the hell are you doing?
Being Gale Weathers.
What the hell are you doing?
- I am Gale Weathers.
- Here's how I see it.
I've got no house, no bodyguard,
no movie, and I'm being stalked.
Because someone wants to kill me?
No, because someone wants to kill you.
So now, starting now,
I go where you go.
That way, if someone wants
to kill me, I'll be with you.
And since they really want to kill you,
they won't kill me, they'll kill you.
- Make sense?
- None.
You know, in the movies,
I play you as being much smarter.
And as a sane person.
Foryou, that must be quite a stretch.
- That's funny.
- Ha!
- Need to get in that building?
- Yeah.
- Is there a story in that building?
- Maybe.
Gale Weathers would find a way.
Bitch. All right, wait.Just--
Don't tell me what to do.
Basements, wow.
Basements creep me out.
You'd make
a fascinating interview.
Hello?
Hi. Excuse me.
I am Gale Weathers...
and I'm here researching
with the police this photo.
It was taken at the studio.
Her name is Maureen Prescott.
Back then it was probably Roberts.
- Hey, are you--
- No.
- But you look just--
- Like her?
- I've been hearing it all my life.
- It's uncanny.
I was up for Princess Leia.
I was this close.
So, who gets it?
The one who sleeps with George Lucas.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to bring up
a-a sore subject for you.
Sure, you didn't.
None of them did.
So, how can I help you? Or do you want
me to tell you who you look like?
How about some information
on Maureen Roberts?
I don't work for the cops, sweetie.
I work for the studio.
Really? Well,
would you work for...
the president?
The president of the studio.
Fifty dollars? Who are you?
A reporter for Woodsboro High?
It's worth two grand.
Are you gonna help
Gale Weathers or not?
I know every face in here.
I got a respect
for the unknown actor.
If they're looking for Maureen Roberts,
they're never gonna find her.
Rina Reynolds they will.
Rina Reynolds.
Stage name.
You should talk,Judy Jurgenstern.
What are these movies?
Amazombies, Space Psycho...
Creatures from the San Andreas Fault.
Horror pictures
back in Milton's heyday.
- Back in what?
-John Milton.
The horror producer?
Those were his movies.
Come on, Sid.
Oh, my God!
Sidney Prescott!
Oh, my God! I'm Angelina Tyler.
I'm you! I mean, I'm not.
I mean, I was.
I-I thought-- Well,
if there's no movie...
then no one would care
if I took some souvenirs.
Souvenirs?
I may never win another role,
so these may be...
my only memories,
you know, of Hollywood.
I-I know it's weird 'cause
it's your life and all, but...
I wanted to make you proud, Sidney.
Oh. Well,
I'm sure I would've been.
The real Sidney.
The real person.
I wish--
I wish it would've worked out.
Hey--
Angelina?
Hello?
Close call.
What are you doing here?
It occurred to me that I've never
snuck through your bedroom window.
See what you do to me?
What have I done to you?
About the, uh, sex stuff?
You know, I'm not trying
to rush you at all.
Would you settle for
a PG-13 relationship?
Dewey!
Sidney, I'm in here.
Over here.
Yes. Mother will protect you
from the bogeyman.
Come into the bedroom.
Hide in Mommy's bed.
I lied, Sidney.
I can't protect you at all.
You don't deserve to be protected!
You didn't protect me!
We did your mom a favour, Sid.
That woman was a slutbag whore...
who flashed her shit all over town
like she was Sharon Stone.
'Cause let's face it, Sidney,
your mother was no Sharon Stone.
- Sidney's mother was fucking my father.
- Sid, where are you?
Dewey!
Dewey, help me!
Sidney? Give Mommy a kiss
and we'll make up.
- No!
- Sidney!
Sid!
Sid, are you okay?
What happened?
The killer's in the house, Dewey.
He's upstairs.
- And my mother--
- Let's go, let's go.
I heard her voice.
I saw her, Dewey.
- Upstairs. Come on, let's go.
- It's okay, Sid.
You weren't supposed
to go in that house.
It's all set up for the murder scene.
- I'm sorry you had to see that.
- He was in there, Dewey.
- He was in there, I swear, I swear.
- You know I believe you.
- What happened?
- Kincaid, hey.
There's nobody up here.
Come on.
- Come on.
- Okay, so I stole the mask.
Whatever. I didn't know you got
the gas chamber for that.
- You stole the mask?
- I took it.
- You took the mask
or you stole the mask?
- I-I took it as like a souvenir.
- Don't look at me. I didn't take shit.
- I know he was there.
I am not dreaming,
I am not crazy.
- He was there in Woodsboro.
- That's not Woodsboro, Sidney.
You know what I mean. But he was there.
He or she, or whoever this is.
We're gonna take you back
to the station, keep you under watch.
Put you in a safe house.
Whatever it takes.
Come on.
It's all right, Sid.
We all believe you.
- He's watching.
- And he wants you.
- Hey, Dew.
- Dew.
- Come on.
- We have to go catch up with Sid.
- Take a look at this first.
- Someone we know?
- Where'd you get this?
- We got it. Archives.
- Sidney's mother was an actress.
Three movies.
-Horror movies.
-Wanna know who produced all three?
-Who?
- There'll be other movies, Roman.
- Not only did they--
did they kill the film,
but they killed my cast.
Now, nobody's gonna wanna work
with me. Variety called me a pariah.
I don't even know what a pariah is.
Why-Why couldn't someone
have killed the cast from Stab 1?
Huh? Or Stab 2? Why me?
What--John, what did we do wrong?
Hollywood is full of criminals
whose careers are flourishing.
I'm not a criminal!
I was questioned.
Yeah, but that's all.
I was questioned. That's it.
- That's good foryour mystique.
- You think it will help me get work?
Roman. John.
Jennifer, and guests.
To what do I owe the honour?
- Rina Reynolds.
- Rina Reynolds? Who's Rina Reynolds?
Why don't you head to the house?
Tell everybody not to cut
the cake without me.
- Oh, God, I forgot. Your birthday.
- Yeah.
- Happy birthday, Roman.
- Yeah, as if life isn't tragic enough.
Shut the doors behind you, please.
So, you knew
Sidney Prescott's mother.
- Who?
- Rina Reynolds?
Do you know how many actors have
worked for me? Hundreds. Thousands.
- He didn't say she was an actor.
- Good catch.
- So what's the point?
- Uh, no point.
I'm just gonna give, uh,
Detective Kincaid a call.
I remember. She was a bit player
in a couple of my movies.
- A nobody. So what does it matter?
- Oh, come on.
You have made millions
off the story of her murder.
You're obsessed with her,
and you're obsessed with her daughter!
All right, easy, Geraldo.
Why don't you tell us the truth?
What the hell are you guys getting at?
I make horror films, that's what I do.
The studio came to me with Stab.
They came to me.
Check it out.
- But you knew who she was.
- When we did the first Stab...
I realized I had known
Maureen Prescott before.
I mean, as Rina.
I couldn't tell anyone.
Can you imagine the press?
And now?
I mean, murders on your set.
- And-And still you say nothing?
- Get real.
- That would make me a suspect.
-Just because you knew her?
- Yeah.
- I don't think so.
Just what did happen to Maureen
when she was in Hollywood?
Now, you listen to me, Lois Lane.
Let it go. It's dead and buried.
How would you like to see it
dug up on national TV?
Why don't you tell me
what happened?
It was in the '70s.
Everything was different.
I was well-known for my parties.
Rina knew what they were.
It was for girls like her to meet men.
Men who could get them parts...
if they made
the right impression.
Nothing happened to her
that she didn't invite...
in one way or another
no matter what she said afterwards.
- Are you saying she--
- I'm saying things got out of hand.
Maybe they did take advantage of her.
You know, Maybe the sad truth is...
this is not the city
for innocents.
No charges were brought.
And the bottom line is...
Rina Reynolds
wouldn't play by the rules.
You wanna get ahead in Hollywood?
You gotta play the game, or go home.
What do you know
about trilogies?
- You mean, like movie trilogies?
- You seem to like movies, Detective.
Call me Mark, would you? 'Cause
I'm gonna keep calling you Sidney.
I'll call you Mark when
you catch the killer, Detective.
All I know about movie trilogies
is that in the third one...
all bets are off.
- Did you request this case?
- No. They tend to put me...
on the ones that deal
with the business.
I grew up here,
and I know my way around the studios.
Huh.
Must be exciting.
Beautiful place, beautiful people.
To me, Hollywood is about death.
Excuse me?
I'm a homicide detective, remember?
And when you see what I see
day in and day out...
the violence
that people do to each other...
you get haunted.
I think you know about that.
What do you mean?
I know what it's like
to see ghosts that don't go away.
To be watching a scary movie in
your head, whether you want to or not.
Watching it alone.
Ghosts are tough.
You can't shoot ghosts.
Can't arrest ghosts.
But the best way to stop being
haunted is to be with people.
You're here, you're not hiding.
You've done the right thing,
Miss Prescott.
What did you know about your mother?
I always thought
I had the perfect mom.
Perfect family.
Till I found out I was wrong.
She, um--
She had a secret life, and I tried
to understand that, and, um...
soon as I thought that I had,
more secrets.
I don't know who my mom was.
You know who she was to you.
Here's the deal.
I'm off to search the set.
I think what you saw is real.
That's the good news.
- How is that good news?
- Because that means...
that we're dealing with
an ordinary flesh-and-blood killer.
- And I know how
to handle guys like that.
- Oh, yeah? How?
Catch him or kill him.
Hey, Detective.
What's your favourite
scary movie?
My life.
Mine too.
We have to think.
Strategize.
- Milton's the key to everything.
- He's a pervert, he's not a killer.
He's gotta be involved somehow.
We should follow him.
We're gonna go back to the precinct and
we're gonna tell Kincaid and Sidney...
what we found out.
My Gale would be much more aggressive.
My Gale would suspect everybody.
- My Gale would--
- Shut up!
- Riley here.
- Dewey, it's Sidney.
- Hey, Sid.
- I'm with Gale.
We're on our way to see you.
- No.
Listen, I'm not at the station.
John Milton called me and said
he had something to tell me.
Something about my mom.
I'm going to meet him at his house.
Wait, Sid, I'm not so sure
that's a good idea.
It's okay. Kincaid's with me.
I've got official big-time...
L.A.P.D. protection, but
I'd feel better if you were there.
- We're on our way, but still, Sid--
- Thanks.
- What?
- Looks like we're going
to that party after all.
Hey, guys. Come on in.
Join the party.
Yeah, well, actually,
we're here to see Sidney.
- Really? Sidney's here.
- Where?
- Where's Sidney?
- She's right there!
Jesus!
Not "Sidney," Sidney.
- Like I'm "Gale" and she's Gale.
- Sidney Prescott?
- Yeah.
- No, I'd never invite her here.
- She's on her way.
- Well, the more the merrier.
God, this house is incredible.
-It's old Hollywood.
-Yeah. Could the dude have more money?
Supposedly, Milton has
a secret screening room...
that was like the scene
back in the '70s, you know.
It was, like, drinks and drugs
and girls and movies and shit.
Wow! Wish I could've seen it.
Big old screening room
shouldn't be too hard to find.
I'm gonna go--
I'm gonna go check this place out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Just one damn minute.
There's a psycho killer on the loose.
And you want to go traipsing around
this gigantic mansion?
Have you ever actually seen
the Stab movies? Every time...
this dude enters a room,
he ends up a goddam shish kebab.
- I'll go with you, Roman.
- There you go. You guys wanna come?
It'll be okay.
We're gonna stick together.
-You're not stickin'. Wait up.
-We're gonna stay here and wait for Sid.
We'll be right back!
If-If you were a screening room...
where would you be?
I bet in the basement.
I don't like basements.
Ooh, it's spooky.
- Ooh, Weredad.
- Damn, it's dark in here.
- I loved that movie.
- Forget the movie!
What if Milton's crazy...
and he's gonna jump outta his screening
room with a sling blade or something?
- He won't.
- You sure about that?
- What's down there?
- Zombies and aliens.
You know, what you look like
without make-up, Jennifer.
Jesus. Stop pretending
I wasn't the best you've ever had.
- Oh, stop pretending I even remember.
- Stop pretending!
Roman?
- Any sign of her?
- No.
This is so strange.
It sure is.
Dewey, do you have caller I.D.
on your cell phone?
-Yeah.
-All right, use it and-and press "send."
What the hell?
What is this thing?
Is this what he--
What the hell?
Dewey, he's got our voices.
He's got Sid.
He's got us all.
- Oh, my God. We gotta find her.
- Come on.
All right, take the gun.
Go find Roman and Jennifer.
I'm gonna get the others.
- Be careful.
- You too.
Tyson! Angelina!
You up there?
- Roman!
- Tyson!
Angelina!
Damn it!
Okay, come on.
We gotta get out of here.
- Where's Angelina?
- I don't know. She went in here.
- I came in after her. Now she's gone.
- Great.
- What's wrong?
- Looks like Stab 3
is back in production.
Roman!
Jennifer!
Roman?
- Is he dead?
- Yeah, very.
Dewey! Dewey!
Dewey?
Dewey!
God, I'm sorry.
Jennifer, Gale, look.
- I found a secret passage.
- Roman's dead.
- What?
- The killer's here.
- Come on.
- Let go of me! I'm getting out of here!
- You're not safe alone!
Listen to me!
I did not fuck that pig Milton
to get a leading role...
just to die here with second-rate
celebrities like you two!
- Gale! I'm up here.
- Come on.
- Dewey!
- You guys should get out too.
It's crazy to still be here.
- Wait!
- Come on!
- Dewey!
- Gale, Jennifer, up here!
Dewey, here.
He got Roman and Angelina too.
- We'll be safer if we
stick together, won't we?
- Of course. Why--
What's goin' on?
Oh, shit!
- Hey!
- Dewey!
Dewey!
No!
Help! Police!
Help! Help!
Police! Help!
Oh, you motherfucker!
Damn!
Dewey! Dewey!
Behind the mirror, Dewey!
Gale! Get away! Dewey!
- Do you hear something?
- Get away from me, you asshole.
- Get away from me! You don't scare me!
- Look, Gale. The mirror's moving.
- Gale! Gale!
- Stand back, Gale.
You can't kill me. I'm the killer
in Stab 3. I'm the killer!
Gale, cover!
Dewey!
- Tyson!
I'm gonna check down here.
You call for help.
Okay.
Tyson!
- Tyson?
- Any sign of him?
- No.
- All right. I'm gonna check out front.
Dew--
Gale!
- Dewey?
- Gale!
Gale!
- Who is this?
- Dewey, it's me.
Gale, where are you?
I'm in the basement.
I'm trapped.
- Where?
- There's a door in the kitchen.
Hurry.
Wait. How do I know this is
you, Gale, and not the killer?
Dewey, open the fucking door.
It's me.
Well, don't you think that's
what the killer would say?
Come on. He's out cold
at the bottom of the stairs.
Hey!
Dewey. Dewey.
All right, all right.
It's pizza, not a party.
Everybody get back to work.
Anybody seen my fuckin' partner?
Hey, Morgan,
what did you pay?
- Hello?
- Who is this?
- Um, w-who's calling?
Gale, Dewey, whoever, um, call me back.
I can only hear myself.
I only hear you too, Sidney.
- Who is this?
- The question isn't who I am.
The question is:
Who's with me?
- Sidney, stay away!
- Sidney!
Don't do it. If you do one thing
to attract attention to yourself...
one thing,
I'll kill them both.
Now, do you have somewhere
we can be alone?
- Yes.
- Yeah. Go there.
Oh, it's hard being friends
with you, Sidney.
When you're friends with Sidney,
you die.
Well, these friends don't have to,
Sidney. It's up to you.
- How do I know their voices are--
- Are real?
How do you know
you're not hearing things?
How do you know I'm not someone
in your head? Somewhere you know.
- Don't come here, Sidney!
- Dewey!
- Or do you?
- You're dead.
I don't want them.
I want you.
It's simple.
You show yourself, they survive.
- You run, they die.
- Oh, God!
Don't you wanna know, Sidney,
who killed her?
Don't you wanna know
who killed your mother?
- Have you seen Kincaid?
- Yeah, I saw him go out.
- Wallace is still lookin' for him.
- Where?
She'd have been so happy, Sidney,
to know we'd be together.
- Where?
- I'll call you when you're on your way.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
Holy shit.
- What?
- You follow directions well, Sidney.
Now, welcome to the final act.
See that metal detector?
Use it.
All over, Sidney.
Everywhere.
The other leg too.
Show it to me.
Throw it in the pool.
Now, come inside, Sidney.
No fucking way. How do I know
they're not dead already?
They're right inside,
waiting for you.
Look for yourself.
Now that we're all here,
the party can begin.
- Dewey.
- Sid.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
He's right there!
Oh, shit.
Think again.
It's your turn to scream, asshole.
Yeah!
- It's okay.Just give me a second.
- Okay.
- Hurry, Sid.
- Sidney? Sidney?
Where is he?
Be careful!
I heard shots. Tyson's dead.
What's goin' on?
- What're you doin' here, Kincaid?
- Lookin' for you.
Tyson said there was a party here
tonight, and I thought, uh-oh.
Third act celebration.
Thought I better check it out.
Alone?
Where's your partner?
Hey, Miss Prescott.
I'm here to help.
Put the gun down.
No!
Sid! Wake up, Sid!
Sid, come on!
- Wake up!
- Sidney!
Sid, shoot him! Sid!
Shoot the fucker!
Shoot him!
You want me, motherfucker?
Come and get me.
Run!
Sid.
Come in here, please.
It's just me, Sid.
Oh, I was so pretty.
Everybody loved me.
Have you missed me, Sidney?
Would you like to hold me
one last time?
What's the matter?
What are you staring at?
Don't you remember your mother?
You're not going anywhere, Sidney.
It's time you came to terms
with me and with Mother.
Maybe you never
knew her at all, Sidney.
Maybe you just can't get past
the surface of things.
- Who the hell are you?
- The other half of you.
I searched for a mother too,
an actress named Rina Reynolds.
Tried to find her my whole life.
And four years ago,
I actually tracked her down.
Knocked at her door, thinking
she'd welcome me with open arms.
But she had a new life
and a new name: Maureen Prescott.
You were the only child
she claimed, Sidney.
She shut me out
in the cold forever.
Her own son.
Roman Bridger, director.
And brother.
She slammed the door in my face, Sid.
She said I was Rina's child...
and Rina was dead.
And it struck me.
What a good idea!
So I watched her.
I made a little home movie.
A little-little family film.
It seems Maureen--
Mom--
She really got around.
I mean, Cotton was one thing.
Everybody knew about that.
But Billy's father?
That was the key.
Your boyfriend didn't like seeing
his daddy in my film too much.
He didn't like it at all.
But once I supplied the motivation,
all the kid needed was a few pointers.
Have a partner to sell out in case
you get caught, find someone to frame.
It was like
he was making a movie.
You. This is all because ofyou.
I'm a director, Sid.
- I direct.
- Oh.
I had no idea that they were
gonna make a film of their own.
- Oh, shit.
- What a film it turned out to be, huh?
I mean, introducing Sidney,
the victim.
Sidney, the survivor.
Sidney, the star!
All right. You're gonna be all right.
Just apply pressure.
Here, take this.
Get the son ofa bitch.
Let's go.
Fine, you got what you wanted,
hero and villain face-to-face.
- Well, you know what happens now?
The villain dies!
- Exactly!
But I'm not the villain, Sid.
You are.
Here he is, the man who gave away
your mother's innocence.
Huh? What he did
to her made her a slut.
Didn't it? Huh? She never recovered from
that night, right here in this room.
They fucked her three ways from Sunday.
Ruined her life.
Ruined yours too,
didn't it, Sid?
You hate him, Sid?
Come on, I know you do.
I'm sure you do.
I know who you are.
I know what happened to my mother.
And I want you to understand,
I'm gonna make you pay!
That's what the police are gonna
find on Milton's answering machine...
right next to his lifeless,
mutilated corpse.
- What? Can't hear ya.
- You don't have to do this, Roman.
Just tell me what you want.
I can make it happen.
Any picture.
Name your budget. Script approval.
- Final cut!
- I already have it.
No!
God! You spineless bastard!
No, Sid, that would be you.
You did it all.
You did it, you called them all.
Even your closest friends.
Living in total isolation, the pressure
ofanother movie about you...
the discovery that Milton
destroyed Mommy dearest...
you finally just snapped!
One, two, three!
And who's our hero, huh?
The sole survivor. Who's the one...
who bravely faced down the psychopath
and killed her with her own knife?
You're gonna pay for the life
you stole from me, Sid.
For the mother, and for the family,
and for the stardom and--
Goddam it! Everything you have
that should've been mine!
God! Why don't you stop your whining
and get on with it?
I've heard this shit before!
- Stop!
- You know why you kill people,
Roman? Do you?
- I don't wanna hear it!
- Because you choose to!
There is no one else to blame!
- Stop it! Fucking damn it!
- Why don't you take
some fucking responsibility?
- Fuck you!
Sid? Sidney?
Sidney?
Sidney!
Leave her alone!
Dewey, do something!
- Stand back!
- Dewey!
Sid! Sid.
Sid?
Where is he?
Hey. Lose something?
Found something.
There's gotta be another way in there!
Come on!
You hurt her,
I swear I'll kill you!
-Dewey!
-Down this way. There's another hallway.
There's another door down here.
- This thing's not budging.
- Look around for something heavy.
- Go that way.
- Okay!
I shot you.
I guess we think alike.
Mother's dead.
And there is nothing
you can do about that.
I still got
to make my movie.
Stab 3, right?
Kincaid, hang in there.
Roman? It was Roman?
Be careful, Sid. Randy said
the killer's always superhuman.
Yeah, well,
he wasn't superhuman, Dewey.
He wasn't superhuman at all.
- You can't fuckin' kill me!
- Head!
- Head! Head, Dewey!
- What?
Head!
Shoot him in the head.
Thanks.
No problem.
Look.
Come on, Cherokee.
Come on.
- Yeah, she's doin' great.
- Yeah.
Look.
What are you doing with that?
Um, will you sign it
for me, Gale?
You hate that book.
Besides, I'm-l'm done
with that kind of reporting.
For me.
Will you sign it for me?
You're a nut.
Okay.
- Will you?
- Dewey.
I know it'll never work,
and you know it'll never work.
But what I'm asking is
just to see ifwe're wrong.
We don't know everything, Gale.
I mean, you thinkyou do, but--
You're a brave man,
Dewey Riley.
I'm really scared right now.
Inside.
Sid, we've been waiting for you.
We're gonna start a movie.
- What kind of movie?
- You have to come and see.
Take a little walk
to the edge of town
Now, spread your wings and fly
Don't the lights of the city
look so damn pretty
When you're flyin' so high
It's hard to know
about there down below
The streets fade
They're swimmin'deep in blood
It seems to make me
groan and cry
You really wanna know
what's wrong with this land
Just scratch your head
with your red right hand
I'm talkin'about blood, babe
It's in your veins
Your mommy and daddy
They've got the same
You're under the mirror
day after day
You see a pretty face
crumblin' away
As you become
your mom and daddy
Scream once, scream twice
Now scream again
Cover that face
with your red right hand
So, is this the end
Forus, my friend
Well as though we rise
As the day breaks the dawn
And as the moon hides the sun
Oh, the sun
No more sorrow
All those crying days are gone
Now it'sgone
So, is this the end
Forus, my friend
Spoke to my god today
Asked him why he'd gone away
Hitched on a rocket ride
into the sun
Said, son I got one for ya
Down there in California
Just take a look around
at all you've done
You're automatic
like a burnin' gun
You're a star like everyone
Talked to my soul today
Couldn't keep my brain away
So I found a holiday
behind the sun
Took all the friends I could
Spun out in Hollywood
Hit up on a climate everyone
You're automatic
like a burnin' gun
You're a star like everyone
You could save the world
Could be shining on my pearl
Just might find your way
mypearl
Shine
You're automatic
like a burnin' gun
You're a star like everyone
You could save the world
Could be shinin' on my pearl
Just might find your way
my pearl